<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.mijug.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.mijug.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-08-01T18:29:15-04:00</updated><id>https://www.mijug.net/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Information Just Under Glass</title><subtitle>MIJUG.NET serves the communities of Southeast Michigan, Ohio, and Florida with technology, sustainability, and community engagement resources. A platform by Kranson Enterprises for sharing knowledge and connecting communities.</subtitle><author><name>Bob Kranson</name></author><entry><title type="html">Documentation Guide - Navigate Our Knowledge Base</title><link href="https://www.mijug.net/documentation/navigation/2025/07/30/documentation-guide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Documentation Guide - Navigate Our Knowledge Base" /><published>2025-07-30T14:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-01T16:35:54-04:00</updated><id>https://www.mijug.net/documentation/navigation/2025/07/30/documentation-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.mijug.net/documentation/navigation/2025/07/30/documentation-guide.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="documentation-guide---navigate-our-knowledge-base">Documentation Guide - Navigate Our Knowledge Base</h1>

<p>Welcome to your complete guide for navigating our documentation! This page serves as your roadmap to all the tutorials, guides, and resources available in our knowledge base.</p>

<!-- excerpt-start -->

<p>Whether you’re just getting started or looking for advanced techniques, our documentation is organized to help you find exactly what you need. From development setup to content management, we’ve got you covered.</p>

<!-- excerpt-end -->

<h2 id="-documentation-overview">📚 Documentation Overview</h2>

<p>Our documentation is structured to support different learning paths and use cases. Here’s how to navigate our knowledge base effectively:</p>

<h2 id="-quick-start-paths">🎯 Quick Start Paths</h2>

<h3 id="for-new-users">For New Users</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="/docs/getting-started/">Getting Started</a></strong> - Essential setup and first steps</li>
  <li><strong><a href="/docs/welcome-mijug-workspace/">Welcome to MIJUG Workspace</a></strong> - Understand our platform</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="for-developers">For Developers</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="/docs/getting-started/">Getting Started</a></strong> - Development environment setup</li>
  <li><strong><a href="/docs/liquid-tags-examples/">Liquid Tags Examples</a></strong> - Jekyll templating</li>
  <li><strong><a href="/docs/frontmatter-cms/">FrontMatter CMS Usage</a></strong> - Content management</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="for-content-creators">For Content Creators</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="/docs/frontmatter-cms/">FrontMatter CMS Usage</a></strong> - Learn the CMS interface</li>
  <li><strong><a href="/docs/liquid-tags-examples/">Liquid Tags Examples</a></strong> - Advanced content features</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="for-accessibility-focus">For Accessibility Focus</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="/docs/accessibility-testing/">Accessibility Testing</a></strong> - WCAG compliance and testing</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="-documentation-by-topic">📋 Documentation by Topic</h2>

<h3 id="development--setup">Development &amp; Setup</h3>

<ul class="topic-list">

  <li><a href="/docs/accessibility-testing/">Accessibility Testing Configuration</a> - Comprehensive accessibility testing setup with WCAG 2.1 AA compliance using axe-core and Playwright</li>

  <li><a href="/docs/frontmatter-cms/">FrontMatter CMS Usage</a> - Learn how to use the FrontMatter CMS extension for content management in Jekyll</li>

  <li><a href="/docs/getting-started/">Getting Started</a> - Quick setup guide for the MIJUG .NET workspace</li>

  <li><a href="/docs/liquid-tags-examples/">Liquid Tags Examples</a> - Comprehensive examples of Liquid tag usage in Jekyll</li>

  <li><a href="/docs/welcome-mijug-workspace/">Workspace Home</a> - Workspace project for VSCode to develop the target site.</li>

</ul>

<h3 id="platform--tools">Platform &amp; Tools</h3>

<ul>
  <li><a href="/docs/welcome-mijug-workspace/">Welcome to MIJUG Workspace</a> - Platform overview</li>
  <li><a href="/docs/liquid-tags-examples/">Liquid Tags Examples</a> - Jekyll templating reference</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="quality--testing">Quality &amp; Testing</h3>

<ul>
  <li><a href="/docs/accessibility-testing/">Accessibility Testing</a> - WCAG compliance and testing tools</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="-find-what-you-need">🔍 Find What You Need</h2>

<h3 id="by-difficulty-level">By Difficulty Level</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Beginner</strong>: Getting Started, Welcome to MIJUG Workspace</li>
  <li><strong>Intermediate</strong>: FrontMatter CMS Usage, Liquid Tags Examples</li>
  <li><strong>Advanced</strong>: Accessibility Testing, Custom Development</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="by-time-investment">By Time Investment</h3>

<ul>
  <li><strong>5 minutes</strong>: Welcome to MIJUG Workspace</li>
  <li><strong>15 minutes</strong>: Getting Started, FrontMatter CMS Usage</li>
  <li><strong>30+ minutes</strong>: Liquid Tags Examples, Accessibility Testing</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="-need-help">📞 Need Help?</h2>

<p>Can’t find what you’re looking for? Here are your options:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Search</strong>: Use the site search to find specific topics</li>
  <li><strong>Categories</strong>: Browse by <a href="/categories/">documentation category</a></li>
  <li><strong>Tags</strong>: Explore content by <a href="/tags/">topic tags</a></li>
  <li><strong>Contact</strong>: <a href="/contact/">Reach out to our team</a> for personalized help</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="-contributing-to-documentation">🚀 Contributing to Documentation</h2>

<p>Found an error or want to improve our docs? We welcome contributions:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Documentation source is in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">docs/_docs/</code> directory</li>
  <li>Use the FrontMatter CMS for easy editing</li>
  <li>Follow our content style guide for consistency</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p><em>This documentation guide is automatically updated as new content is added. Bookmark this page for quick access to our latest resources!</em></p>]]></content><author><name>MIJUG Team</name></author><category term="documentation" /><category term="navigation" /><category term="docs" /><category term="guide" /><category term="navigation" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Your complete guide to navigating and using our documentation. Find tutorials, guides, and resources organized by topic and difficulty.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.mijug.net/assets/logo-mijug-watermark-98x100.svg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.mijug.net/assets/logo-mijug-watermark-98x100.svg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Reusing Older Computers in 2025</title><link href="https://www.mijug.net/linux/2025/07/18/reusing-older-computers-in-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reusing Older Computers in 2025" /><published>2025-07-18T16:39:43-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-30T22:54:37-04:00</updated><id>https://www.mijug.net/linux/2025/07/18/reusing-older-computers-in-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.mijug.net/linux/2025/07/18/reusing-older-computers-in-2025.html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past, the type of computer you owned was largely determined by the silicon chips inside it. Mainframes, workstations, PCs, Macs, microcomputers, and minicomputers were all defined by their chipsets. Companies like IBM, Sun Microsystems, Intel, Hewlett-Packard, Texas Instruments, and Apple created hardware that was compatible with specific operating systems.</p>

<h3 id="chips">Chips</h3>

<p>Fast forward to 2025, and chip technology has advanced dramatically. Central processing units (CPUs) have become faster, with names like i5, i7, CoreDuo, and M1. Meanwhile, graphical processing units (GPUs), originally designed for gaming and rendering, are now essential for artificial intelligence (AI) applications. This rapid evolution has driven a relentless pace of change, particularly in security.</p>

<h3 id="the-security-race">The Security Race</h3>

<p>As computing power increases, so does the ability to crack passwords. Tasks that once required a single home computer can now be accomplished faster with rented cloud computers—or even multiple rented computers across cloud providers. This has necessitated the development of new security measures, such as the Trusted Platform Module (TPM) chip, which is a minimum requirement for Windows 11.</p>

<h4 id="trusted-platform-module---tpm">Trusted Platform Module - TPM</h4>

<p>Do you have a TPM chip in your current PC? Maybe. You’ll need to check via an internet connection and a Windows 10 update to find out. But why is a TPM chip so important? The answer lies in quantum computing. Quantum technology is on the horizon, promising to process data at speeds that could render traditional security measures obsolete. A task that might take thousands of computers days or years to complete could be done in seconds with quantum computing.</p>

<h3 id="why-keep-your-old-computer">Why Keep Your Old Computer?</h3>

<p>While new security requirements may render older computers unsuitable for sensitive tasks like banking or business, they can still serve a purpose. Many everyday activities—like playing music, viewing photos, or casual gaming—don’t require the latest security features. Repurposing your old computer for these non-sensitive tasks can provide significant value:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Reduce Electronic Waste</strong>: Reusing your old computer delays the need to dispose of it, helping to reduce e-waste.</li>
  <li><strong>Transition Gracefully</strong>: Use your old computer as a staging ground to offload, back up, and format data before moving to a new device.</li>
  <li><strong>Extend Its Life</strong>: Repurpose your old investment for new uses:
    <ul>
      <li>Let grandkids play games on it.</li>
      <li>Turn it into a garage PC for music and video.</li>
      <li>Use it for anonymous internet browsing to reduce tracking and targeted ads on your primary devices.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h3>

<p>Reusing older computers is not just about nostalgia—it’s a practical way to maximize your investment, reduce waste, and adapt to changing technology. While they may no longer meet the demands of modern security, these devices still have plenty of life left for everyday, non-sensitive tasks. So before you toss that old PC, consider how it might still serve you in 2025 and beyond.</p>]]></content><author><name>Bob Kranson</name></author><category term="linux" /><category term="cpus" /><category term="gpus" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping your chips out of the wood chipper]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.mijug.net/assets/logo-mijug-watermark-98x100.svg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.mijug.net/assets/logo-mijug-watermark-98x100.svg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to MIJUG.NET!</title><link href="https://www.mijug.net/announcements/2025/07/03/welcome-to-mijug-dot-net.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to MIJUG.NET!" /><published>2025-07-03T15:05:55-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-30T22:54:37-04:00</updated><id>https://www.mijug.net/announcements/2025/07/03/welcome-to-mijug-dot-net</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.mijug.net/announcements/2025/07/03/welcome-to-mijug-dot-net.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="hello">Hello!</h3>

<p>Welcome to <a href="https://www.mijug.net">MIJUG.NET</a>, a platform dedicated to serving the communities of southeast Michigan, Ohio, and Florida.</p>

<h3 id="locations">Location(s)</h3>

<p>As the proprietor of this site, I am based in southeast Michigan and occasionally travel to Ohio and Florida. This site is designed to share knowledge, resources, and updates relevant to these regions, with a focus on technology, sustainability, and community engagement.</p>

<h3 id="thank-you">Thank You!</h3>

<p>Thank you for visiting, and I look forward to connecting with you!</p>]]></content><author><name>Bob Kranson</name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome Announcement for My Information Just Under Glass - MIJUG.NET]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.mijug.net/assets/logo-mijug-watermark-98x100.svg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.mijug.net/assets/logo-mijug-watermark-98x100.svg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>