<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-23T11:01:16-04:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">My Information Just Under Glass</title><subtitle>Computer related information and blogging content.</subtitle><author><name>Bob Kranson</name></author><entry><title type="html">Reusing Older Computers in 2025</title><link href="/linux/2025/07/18/reusing-older-computers-in-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reusing Older Computers in 2025" /><published>2025-07-18T16:39:43-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-18T16:39:43-04:00</updated><id>/linux/2025/07/18/reusing-older-computers-in-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="/linux/2025/07/18/reusing-older-computers-in-2025.html"><![CDATA[<p>Many years ago each type of computer was really based on who created the silicon chips put inside. Mainframe, Workstation, PC, MAC, Micro-Computer, Mini-Computer, Macintosh, etcetera…</p>

<p>There was IBM, Sun Microsystems, Intel, Hewlett-Packard, Texas Instruments, Apple and a few others. The chipset made the computer hardware compatible with a given operating system.</p>

<p>Now, in 2025, the chips have sped their way to faster central processing units (CPUS) with varying names (i5, i7, CoreDuo, M1) and have incorporated even faster graphical processing units (GPUS) which are targeted for gaming and graphical manipulation or rendering though have become ubiquitous with the current Artificial Intelligence (AI) domain.</p>

<p>This speed of change has required a brutal pace to ensure security. How fast can you crack a password? What if you wanted to do it with you home computer? Maybe it could be done with a rental computer (aka cloud)? Or many rented computers (aka many computers in any number of cloud providers)? This is all possible. So possible they have created another chip to separate concerns for security - Trusted Module Platform or TPM chip. This is the minimum requirement for Windows 11. Do you have one in your current Personal Computer? Maybe. You will have to update it via an internet connection via Windows 10 operating system and find out.</p>

<p>Why do we need a TPM? Quantum is coming, that’s why. No, it’s not the star from the TV show “Quantum Leap”. Its the capability to process so many numbers, letters, digits so fast that it can replace 1000’s of computers processing time for days and years into seconds.</p>

<p>Why keep my old computer? Do you play music on it? Do you view pictures on it? Do you play games on it? Likely a few things you do on the computer are not “security sensitive” like banking, investing, financing, legal, or business activities would be. You can still use it for those no-security things in your day to day life.</p>

<p>Taking time to re-use your old computer for non-secure basic activities will provide you this value:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Delay or defer creating more electronic waste</li>
  <li>Provide a cut-off point to off-load, backup, and format your old computer to something new</li>
  <li>Breathe a different life into that investment you made X years ago
    <ul>
      <li>Grandkids can play games</li>
      <li>That old garage stereo can now become a garage PC with video AND music</li>
      <li>You can do not-logged-in-as-you internet surfing to keep tracking and ads focused away from your “personal” device(s)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Bob Kranson</name></author><category term="linux" /><category term="cpus" /><category term="gpus" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping your chips out of the wood chipper]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to MIJUG.NET!</title><link href="/announcements/2025/07/03/welcome-to-mijug-dot-net.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to MIJUG.NET!" /><published>2025-07-03T15:05:55-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-03T15:05:55-04:00</updated><id>/announcements/2025/07/03/welcome-to-mijug-dot-net</id><content type="html" xml:base="/announcements/2025/07/03/welcome-to-mijug-dot-net.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.mijug.net">MIJUG.NET</a> is a site built to serve primarily south east Michigan, Ohio, and Florida.</p>

<p>As proprietor of the site I live in south east Michigan. I infrequently travel to Ohio and Florida.</p>]]></content><author><name>Bob Kranson</name></author><category term="announcements" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[MIJUG.NET is a site built to serve primarily south east Michigan, Ohio, and Florida.]]></summary></entry></feed>